（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）蒙武(もうぶ)たちからの連絡が
途絶えたことを懸念した王騎(おうき)は―
Worried over his loss of communication with Meng Wu's group,
Wang Qi hurried forward with his subordinate troops and finally captured the enemy's headquarters!
配下の兵を急がせて 進軍し
ついに 自ら 敵の本陣を捕らえた
だが そこには
蒙武たちの姿も 敵の影もなかった
But there was no sign of Meng Wu's group nor the enemy whatsoever.
Meanwhile, Meng Wu's group that had followed Pang Nuan into the mountains
そのころ 龐煖(ほうけん)を追って
山中に入った蒙武たちは―
was put in desperate straits when they were met with an enemy ambush.
伏兵の攻撃を受けて
窮地に陥っていたのである
本陣を捨てた趙(ちょう)軍が
蒙武たちに―
Wang Qi, aware that the Zhao Army had abandoned their headquarters in order to try to finish off Meng Wu's group,
とどめを刺そうとしていることを
察知した王騎は―
immediately followed after him.
直ちに あとを追った
だが この危急のときにも
王騎は ある違和感を覚えていた
But despite what a critical situation it was, Wang Qi had a certain feeling of discomfort.
（王騎）やはり
かすかに策略の気配を感じます
I do indeed faintly sense a plan.
しかし 現在の趙軍の配置と
その戦い方から考えると―
But if I consider the Zhao Army's current position and method of fighting,
この状況から 大規模な展開を
することは ありえません
there is no way for this situation to develop into anything on a large scale.
Even so, if it poses a threat to me...
それでも なお
私を脅かすとしたら…
張り巡らされた策略は
恐ろしく深い
the strategy they've laid out is phenomenally deep.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）時は紀元前 春秋戦国時代
The setting is before the common era, in the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
名もなき存在から
百人隊の将にまでなった少年 信(しん)は
Xin, the boy that came from obscurity to become the general of a Hundred-Man Unit
激戦の真っただ中で活躍を続け
秦国軍を優勢に導いた
continued to prove himself in the height of battle and led the State of Qin Army to dominance.
だが今
ついに姿を現した敵の総大将は―
But now the enemy Supreme Commander has finally shown himself
想像を絶する存在であった
and is a being beyond imagination.
The name of that man, whom is linked by fate to Wang Qi, is Pang Nuan.
王騎との因縁を持つという
その男の名は“龐煖”
戦局は いよいよ 大きく動きだす
The state of the war has finally started to really shake up.
Presented by Anime-Destiny
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
Translation
kewl0210
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
kewl0210
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Central Performers
（政(せい)）俺に伝えねばならぬこととは
何だ？ 楊端和(ようたんわ)
What is the thing that you must tell me, Yang Duan He?
（楊端和）政…
お前の弟 成蟜(せいきょう)の反乱を共に戦い
Zheng, it has been approximately one year since I fought alongside with you to quell your brother Chengjiao's rebellion.
鎮めてから約１年
我らは山の世界に戻り
戦に明け暮れた
We have returned to the Mountain World and have spent all our time fighting wars.
（楊端和）その結果
我が勢力は かつてなく強大になり
The result of those wars is that my power is greater than it has ever been.
その及ぶ範囲は 北の騎馬民族と
ぶつかる所まで広がった
And the range of that power has expanded to collide with the Northern equestrian tribe.
北の騎馬民族…
Northern equestrian tribe? The Xiongnu?
匈奴(きょうど)か
（楊端和）そうだ
Yes.
匈奴たち 北の騎馬民族は―
The Xiongnu, the Northern equestrian tribe, are a far greater enemy than any Mountain People tribe we have fought in the past.
これまで戦ってきた山の民とは
ワケが違う
Their high level of fighting ability, their deep understanding of the art of war, the large scale of their army...
（楊端和）
彼らは その戦闘能力の高さ―
戦術に対する理解の深さ
軍の規模の大きさ…
Whichever you pick, they are an incomparably stronger fighting tribe.
どれを取ってもケタ違いの
戦闘民族だ
I understand.
承知している
だから ヤツらの勢力範囲に
国境を接している秦(しん) 趙 燕(えん)の各国は
That is why the states that border their sphere of influence,
Qin, Zhao, and Yan,
そこに延々と続く城を築いて
防衛に努めている
are endlessly building castles in an attempt to form a defense.
その匈奴を討つべく―
In an attempt to defeat those Xiongnu,
我らは総力８万の軍を挙げて
彼らの地に攻め入った
we raised an army totaling 80,000 soldiers and invaded their land.
But you are here now.
だが お前たちは 今ここにいる
Does that mean you defeated the Xiongnu?
…ということは
匈奴を討ったのか？
フッ… いや 討てなかった
No, we could not.
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）討てなかったとは？
では 敗れたと？
You couldn't?
Then are you saying you were defeated?
敗れたわけではない
Nor were we defeated.
匈奴軍の主力が
集まっているという地へ赴いたが
We moved our troops to the place that was said to be where the Xiongnu Army's main force was gathered...
but there was no enemy there.
敵がいなかったのだ
There was no... enemy there?
敵がいなかった？
我らは そこで恐ろしいものを見た
それは…
We saw a dreadful sight.
It was...
（楊端和）
10万をはるかに超える匈奴の屍(しかばね)だ
Xiongnu corpses numbering far over 100,000.
Over 100,000... corpses?!
10万を超える屍…
そなたたち山の民が着く前に
何者かが匈奴を討ったのか
So before you Mountain People had arrived, they had been killed by someone else?
だが 何者が… ほかの騎馬民族か？
But who? Another equestrian tribe?
Northern Equestrian Tribe
（昌文君）
ひと口に“北の騎馬民族”というが
We call them the Northern equestrian tribe.
実際には 月氏(げつし) 東胡(とうこ) 匈奴など―
But I have heard there are actually several tribes called Yuezhi, Donghu, Xiongnu and others that are struggling for supremacy.
Yuezhi
Donghu
Xiongnu
さまざまな民族が
覇権を争っていると聞く
（楊端和）初めは 私も そう思った
しかし 違ったのだ
At first, I thought so as well,
but that was incorrect.
What defeated over 100,000 Xiongnu was
10万を超える匈奴を討ったのは…
the Zhao Army forces.
趙の軍勢だった
ハッ…
（昌文君）なに？
What?!
Xiongnu
Zhao
（楊端和）
我らが匈奴の屍を見たのは―
The place we saw the Xiongnu corpses
was nearby a strategic cornerstone protecting the Northern Zhao border, a castle called Yanmen.
趙の北の国境を守る軍事上の要
雁門(がんもん)という城の近く
Yanmen
Xiongnu
Zhao
In other words, the Zhao Army forces that had been sent northward
つまり 北に派遣された趙の軍勢が
匈奴の地に攻め入り 打ちのめした
invaded Xiongnu land and defeated them...
That is what I am saying.
…ということだ
（机をたたく音）
ありえぬ！
Impossible!
我々は 趙の都 邯鄲(かんたん)に
多くの諜報員を送り込んでいる
We have many intelligence operatives sent into Zhao's capital, Handan.
（昌文君）たとえ北の端でも
趙が10万もの大軍と戦を行ったなら
Even if it was at their northern tip, if Zhao sent enough of an army to fight a war against 100,000,
この咸陽(かんよう)にも知らせが入るはずだ
then we would be aware of it here in Xianyang!
だろうな
だが お前たちは現に知らなかった
Indeed... but the fact is that you didn't know.
恐ろしいことだと思わぬか？ 政
Don't you think that is a frightening revelation, Zheng?
（楊端和）
なぜ お前たちは知らぬと思う？
Why do you think you did not know?
趙が情報を封鎖しているからだ
Because Zhao has a blockade on information getting out.
何のために？
For what reason?
（政）北に 匈奴を討つほどの
強力な軍がいることを隠すため
In order to hide the fact that they have an army strong enough to defeat the Xiongnu at the North.
隠して どうする？
（政）隠して…
And by hiding it, what will they do?
By hiding it...
What will they do, knowing that fact is hidden, Zheng?
隠しておいて どうする？ 政
With it hidden...
（政）隠しておいて…
Yanmen
（政）今 展開されている
秦 趙 両国の戦に参入させる
They'll introduce it into the war going on between Qin and Zhao.
If the Qin and Zhao armies are currently struggling for supremacy,
（楊端和）もし今 秦 趙 両軍の
力が拮抗(きっこう)しているとしたら
Qin
Zhao
この新たな軍の出現で
戦は一気に決着がつくだろう
with the appearance of this new army, the war will be settled instantly.
Qin
Zhao
無論 その結果は…
And of course, the result will be...
（机をたたく音）
そんなバカな！
That's insane!
（楊端和）
その軍が南に向かうというのは
あくまで推測だが
The idea that that army will travel South is nothing but a prediction,
もし事実だとしたら―
but if it turns out to be the truth,
それを考え 実行している者は
恐ろしい策略家だ
the one who thought of that plan and enacted it is a fearsome strategist.
（楊端和）そして
趙軍を指揮して 匈奴を討った男も
And he is also the man that directed the Zhao Army and defeated the Xiongnu.
あのとき
匈奴の屍を見て驚いたのは―
When we first discovered them, we were most surprised not by the number of the dead, but how they were killed.
数の多さではなく 殺され方だ
抵抗した形跡もなく
一方的に殺されていた
There was no sign of resistance, they were killed overwhelmingly.
Their defeat was not the result of "military force", it was the result of "strategy".
あれは武の力ではなく
策略によって敗れた結果だ
Do you think it's the work of the same person?
同じ人物の仕業か？
（楊端和）十分 考えられる
It is well within reason.
僅かに生き残った戦士から
聞き出した その男の名は…
I heard the from the few that did survive, that man's name is...
Li Mu.
（楊端和）“李牧(りぼく)”
（李牧）来ましたか
Looks like they're here.
（貂(てん)）ハッ… 何だ？ この音
（蒙毅(もうき)）まさか…
What's this sound?
Could it be...?!
（貂）あれは… 趙の騎馬隊だ！
That's...
a Zhao mounted unit!
なぜ こんな所に？
Why are they at a place like this?
（魏加(ぎか)）
お迎えに上がりました 李牧さま
We're here to pick you up, Lord Li Mu.
あ… あれは…
（李牧）魏加どの ご苦労さまです
That's...
Good work, Lord Wei Jia.
You deceived us, Kaine?!
ダマしたのか？ カイネ！
結構いいヤツだと思ってたのに
敵だったなんて…
I thought you were a pretty good person, but you were an enemy...?
（カイネ）
子供のケンカみたいなこと言うな
Don't talk like this is some kid's spit.
What is happening on this land right now is a war.
今 この地で
行われているのは戦だぞ
殺すのか？ 僕たちを
Are you going to kill us?
安心しろ
Rest easy. Lord Li Mu will not murder people who are not directly related to the war.
李牧さまは 戦に 直接
関わりのない者を殺(あや)めたりはしない
戦が終わりしだい
お前たちは解放される
You two will be released when the war is over.
（カイネ）
じゃあな 河了貂(かりょうてん)　ここでお別れだ
See ya, He Liao Diao.
This is goodbye.
If you really do become a strategist,
お前が本当に軍師なったら
また どこかの戦場で会うかもな
perhaps we'll meet again on a battlefield somewhere.
もちろん 敵として
（貂）クッ…
Of course, that would be as enemies.
あっ それと お前がくれた食べ物
おいしかったぞ
Oh, and the food you gave me was delicious.
（蒙毅）待て！
（カイネ）うん？
Wait!
Please just tell me one thing, Kaine.
ひとつだけ教えてくれ カイネ
李牧とは何者なんだ？
この戦と どう関わっている？
Who is Li Mu?
How is he connected to this war?
質問が２つだな
That was two questions.
いいだろう　１つ目だけ教えてやる
Okay, I'll just answer the first one.
Do you know of people called Zhao's Three Divas?
趙の“三大天”というものを
知っているか？
Of course I know of them.
もちろん知っている
藺相如(りんしょうじょ)　趙奢(ちょうしゃ)　廉頗(れんぱ)…
Lin Xiangru, Zhao She, and Lian Po.
They were great heroes that once fought fierce battles against the State of Qin's Six Great Generals.
かつて我が秦国の六大将軍とも
激しく戦った偉大な英雄たちだ
（蒙毅）だが
藺相如も趙奢も 既に この世になく
But Lin Xiangru and Zhao She have already departed from this world...
廉頗は魏に亡命して
もはや三大天など存在しないはず
And Lian Po fled to Wei. The "Three Great Divas" should no longer exist...
なぜ そんな過去の話を…
Why would you bring up a story of such long past?
確かに
かつての三大天は もういない
It's true that the former Three Great Divas are gone...
But what if a new Three Great Divas were being born...?
だが 新たな三大天が
生まれつつあるとしたら？
まさか 李牧が…
It can't be!
Li Mu is...?!
That's right.
それだよ
State of Zhao Three Great Divas   Li Mu
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）趙軍本陣が
置かれていた所から 南東の方角に
Southeast from where the Zhao Army headquarters was left
there was an area with odd terrain.
変わった地形の場所があった
大きく開けた平地を
切り立った断崖が 三方から―
A large open flatland with sheer cliffs on three sides,
釣り鐘のような形に
囲っているのである
creating a bell-shaped enclosure.
その中で 断崖の麓に追い込まれ
包囲を受けている軍があった
Inside it was an army that had been chased to the foot of a cliff and surrounded.
包囲しているのは
趙軍の中核を成す趙荘(ちょうそう)軍１万2,000
The side doing the encircling was the Zhao Zhuang Army of 12,000, which made up the core of the Zhao Army.
無論 その本陣には趙荘と…
Of course, in the headquarters of that army was Zhao Zhuang and
龐煖がいた
Pang Nuan.
一方 包囲されているのは
蒙武 隆国(りゅうこく)軍
And the ones that were being surrounded were the Meng Wu and Long Guo Armies.
ここに至るまでに 分断され
攻撃され続けた彼らは―
After being were continuously divided until they were brought here,
既に1,000騎未満
they now only have 1,000 mounted soldiers.
And of those remaining, they are all wounded and exhausted.
残った者も
全員が傷つき 疲れ切っていた
（隆国）活路が見いだせぬ
I don't see any means of escape.
Behind us is a sheer cliff which we cannot escape up.
背後は断崖で 逃げ道はなく
敵を突破しようにも―
And as for trying to break through the enemy, not only are the soldiers exhausted,
兵たちには もちろん
蒙武にさえ力が残っておらぬ
but even Meng Wu has no strength left.
もはや これまでか…
Is this... as far as we go?!
This is...!
これは…
（趙荘）来ましたぞ 龐煖さま
He's here... Lord Pang Nuan.
It has been 5 days since the war between the States of Qin and Zhao began.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
秦 趙 両国の戦が始まって５日
ついに 両軍の大将同士が対峙(たいじ)した
And now finally, the Great Generals of the two armies have confronted each other!
（王騎）ここに至るまでに
随分 時間が かかりましたね
It sure took quite a while for us to reach this point, didn't it?
Liao...
You've gotten tired of waiting as well, haven't you, Pang Nuan?
（王騎）あなたも
待ちわびたでしょう？ 龐煖
５日… いや ９年
5 days...
No,
9 years!
さて！
Now, shall we settle this once and for all?
（王騎）
決着をつけるとしましょうか
The time has finally come, hasn't it, Lord Xin?
（渕(えん)）いよいよですね 信どの
（信）ああ
Yeah.
大天旗を掲げよ！
Raise the Great Diva Flag!
Flag: Great Diva
いきなり何だ？ あいつら
What're those guys doing all of a sudden?
（沛浪(はいろう)）あの旗は大天旗！
That flag... It's the Great Diva Flag!
（沛浪）あそこに
趙の三大天がいるってのか？
Does that mean that one of Zhao's Three Great Divas are there?
State of Zhao Three Great Divas   Pang Nuan
Even if he's just offhandedly been called one of the Three Great Divas,
（騰(とう)）にわか三大天でも
その名の効果はあるようですね
that title does seem to have an effect.
フフフッ… 当然でしょう
Of course.
“三大天”の名は
人々の心に刻まれているのです
The title of Three Great Divas is etched into people's hearts,
along with the vibrant battle history of those three being on-par us Six Great Generals of the State of Qin.
私たち秦国の六大将軍とも
互角に渡り合った―
あの３人の輝かしい戦歴と共にね
With the memories that the waving of that Great Diva Flag calls back,
（王騎）
その記憶を呼び覚ます大天旗が
翻れば 士気は跳ね上がりますよ
morale is sure to shoot up.
では こちらも
六大将軍の旗“六将旗”を
Then we should raise the flag of the Six Great Generals, the "Six Generals Flag".
（王騎）そんな物は
ありませんよ 騰 ココココッ…
There is no such thing, Teng.
This really takes me back...
懐かしいですねえ
あの旗を掲げた軍と戦うのは
Fighting an army that has raised that flag...
While we're being nostalgic..
懐かしいついでです
久々にアレをやっておきましょうか
why don't we do that for the first time in quite a while?
This kinda... looks bad!
（信）なんか やべえぞ！
完全に けおされちまってる
なんとかして こっちの勢いを…
They're completely overwhelmed...
We need to do something and add out power to them or...
What're these cheers?
何だ？ この声は
こっちの陣地から聞こえてくるぞ
They're coming from our position!
フフフフッ…
久々に聞きましたよ この声を
It's my first time hearing it in quite a while, these cheers.
さ～て…
Now then...
それでは 早速 始めましょうか
Shall we now get this started?
（政）
こたびの趙との戦には 謎があった
There's a mystery to this war with Zhao.
三大天亡きあとの趙にあって
With the Three Great Divas dead, who was it in Zhao that led an army in an attack on our State of Qin?
大軍を率いて 我が秦国に
攻め入ってきたのは何者なのか
やがて伝わってきた
趙軍 総大将の名は龐煖
We eventually were told that the Zhao Supreme Commander's name is Pang Nuan.
But according to what you told me, that Pang Nuan
だが その龐煖は
お前が語っていたとおり―
“純粋な武の結晶”であり
人を率いるたぐいの者ではなかった
is a pure manifestation of war. Not the kind of person who can lead other people.
そのような男に 一国の
軍の総大将が務まるとは思えぬ
I do not think such a person would be appointed as Supreme Commander for a whole kingdom's army.
ただし 楊端和が
知らせてくれた李牧という男が―
But if this Li Mu man that Yang Duan He informed me of is manipulating the army from the shadows...
影で軍を動かしているとすれば…
Then the mystery is solved...
（昌文君）謎は解けますな
だが もし そうだとすると…
（昌文君）うん？
But... If that is correct...
（政）李牧 尋常な男ではない
Li Mu is not an ordinary man.
10万を超える匈奴を
討ち果たす力を持ちながら―
While he has the power to slay a Xiongnu army of over 100,000,
姿を隠して 秦軍に襲いかかる時を
見計らっている
he is hiding himself and looking for an opportune time to attack the Qin Army.
Why is he going so far to setup a strategy?
なぜ そこまで策略を弄する？
李牧のねらいは 一体 何なのだ？
Just what in the world is Li Mu's goal?
では まずは こちらに
お相手願いましょうか 趙荘さん
Now then, would you mind taking me as your opponent, Mr. Zhao Zhuang?
（士官）
騎馬隊 出陣！ 騰副官に続け！
Mounted unit, depart!
Follow Aide Teng!
The Wang Qi Army's mounted unit is coming!
（趙荘の副官）
王騎軍の騎馬隊 来ます！
Archers, take your positions!
弓兵 構えよ！
（部隊長１）弓兵 構えい！
Archers, take positions!
Fire!
（部隊長１）射(う)て！
右へ かわす
（士官）右方旋回！
Dodge to the right.
Turn to the right!
（部隊長１）左に向かったぞ！
そちらでも矢を放て！
They're heading left!
Fire your arrows that way!
（部隊長２）
間に合わぬ！ 懐に入られた！
They won't make it in time! They're right in our bosom!
（部隊長２）歩兵 構えよ！
Foot soldiers, take positions!
入った！
They're in!
（信）
けど とんでもなく それた所に
入っちまったぞ あの副官
But that aide got led really astray!
That's fine.
（王騎）
フフフッ… あれでいいんですよ
騰の狙いどおりです
That's exactly what Teng was aiming for.
Now then! Next is time for you foot soldiers to take the spotlight.
（王騎）さあ！ 次は
あなたたち歩兵の出番ですよ 童 信
Youngster Xin, I have a big job waiting for you.
大仕事が待っています
（信）えっ？
Lord Zhao Zhuang!
（伝令）趙荘さま！
左の軍より 救援の要請です！
There is a call for reinforcements from the left army!
We cannot stop the momentum of the Wang Qi Army's mounted unit!
突入した王騎軍 騎馬隊の
勢いが止まりません！
Do not panic!
慌てるな　横に敷いた陣は
貫かれることを防ぐのが定石
A horizontally arranged formation will always block against penetration.
（趙荘）横の部隊を
敵前方に回して補強せよ！
Side unit, move in front of the enemy and reinforce the defense!
（士官）騰副官！
奥に厚みを作られました！
Aide Teng! They've created a dense formation further in!
（騰）横に展開する
敵の弓兵を始末するぞ
Spread out horizontally.
We are going to deal with the enemy's archers.
（王騎）頼みましたよ
（信たち）ハッ…
I'm counting on you,
all of you foot soldiers.
歩兵の皆さん
（王騎）全軍 突撃！
All units, charge!
Charge!
突撃だー！
Lord Zhao Zhuang! Foot soldiers from the formation on Wang Qi's right side are advancing!
（趙荘の副官）
趙荘さま！ 王騎軍の右側の陣から
歩兵が前進してきます
Central Army
Right Army
Headquarters
Attack
Left Army
Defend
That Wang Qi...
（趙荘）王騎め…
我が軍の左側が―
He saw through to the fact that the left side of our army is the cornerstone of our defense and attacked it?
守備の要であることを
見抜いて 攻めてきたか
Central Army
Right Army
Headquarters
Attack
まずは この本陣を
守る盾を奪う算段
He's planning to first take away this headquarters' shield...
だが 先ほどの騎馬隊で
楔(くさび)を打ったつもりならば―
But if he intended to drive a wedge in with that mounted unit,
考えが甘いぞ！
then he's too optimistic!
左の全軍 防御体勢！
１歩も下がらず 敵を跳ね返せ！
All left units, defensive positions!
Without retreating one step, deflect the enemy!
（部隊長２）来るぞ！ 前の歩兵は
密集して 敵の突撃に備えよ！
Incoming!
Front foot soldiers, crowd together and prepare for the enemy's charge!
Rear archers, ready your bows!
（部隊長２）
後ろの弓兵は弓を構えい！
Arrows are gonna be coming!
そろそろ矢が来るぞ！
Fire!
（部隊長２）射て！
Now, Feixin Unit!
今だ！ 飛信(ひしん)隊 左に旋回だ！
Turn to the left!
（信）足を止めるな！ 走れ 走れ！
Don't stop for a second!
Run! Run!
（趙荘の副官）あの歩兵たち
本陣に向かってくるぞ
Those foot soldiers... they're heading towards the headquarters!
Left Army
Headquarters
Right Army
So Wang Qi's goal was the headquarters from the beginning?
（趙荘の副官）
王騎のねらいは
最初から この本陣か
だが 敵に横を見せれば
格好の矢の的だ
But showing your side to your enemy makes you quite a target for arrows.
矢が少ないぞ
左の軍の弓兵は何をしているのだ！
There are so few arrows...
What are the left army's archers doing?!
Are you making fun of me, Wang Qi?
（趙荘）
バカにしているのか？ 王騎
If you could just suddenly attack the headquarters from the start and be successful,
いきなり本陣を攻めて成功するなら
誰でも そうする
then anyone would do so.
それが難しいから
周囲から攻めていくのだ
It is because that it's difficult that you start your attack from the surrounding armies?
He may be trying to catch us off guard by attacking the headquarters,
逆に 虚をついて
本陣を狙ったつもりかもしれぬが
but with the speed of foot soldiers, that surprise attack will not get through!
歩兵の足で その奇襲は通用せぬ！
（趙荘）左の軍は守備の要… だが
待ち受けるだけが守備ではないぞ
The left army is the cornerstone of our defense
but simply lying in wait is not defense!
歩兵隊 突撃！
王騎軍 歩兵隊の横腹を食い破れ！
Foot soldier unit, charge!
Bite through the side of the Wang Qi Army's foot soldier unit!
よし！ 敵の歩兵隊を分断したぞ
Good! We've divided the enemy foot soldier unit apart!
（渕）信どの！
Lord Xin!
敵が動いてきましたな
The enemy has moved!
ああ！
全部 王騎将軍の作戦どおりだ！
Yeah...
It's all going according to General Wang Qi's plan!
（信）大仕事？
（王騎）陽動です
Big job?
A diversion.
Perhaps the word "decoy" would be more easy to understand here...
この場合 囮(おとり)と言ったほうが
分かりやすいでしょうか
（王騎）敵の陣形を崩すのに
最も手早い方法は―
The quickest way to destroy an enemy's formation
is to have the enemy move for you on their own.
敵に自ら動いてもらうことです
俺たちに囮になって
敵をおびき出せってことか？
So you want us to be decoys and lure out the enemy?
I think quite a bit of blood will be spilled,
多くの血を
流すことになると思いますが
そうでなくては
相手も出てきません
but unless we do, the enemy will not budge either.
A lot of blood...
（信）多くの血… 今更
血を流すことを恐れたりはしねえが
I'm not scared of shedding blood now after all we've been through,
but if all of us foot soldiers become decoys
俺たち歩兵が全員 囮になって
一体 誰が
実際に敵の本陣を攻撃するんだ？
who exactly is actually going to attack the enemy headquarters?
（王騎）フフフフッ…
決まっているでしょう
Isn't it obvious?
（王騎）私ですよ！
I am!
赤き　血潮
akaki chishio
Crimson blood flowing...
この鼓動は　野望なのか
kono kodou wa yabou na no ka
Is this racing pulse ambition?
幼き日　誓った
osanaki hi chigatta
Even now, I do not waver
夢は今も　揺るがない
yume wa ima mo yuru ga nai
from that dream I dedicated myself to in my youth.
命が燃える
inochi ga moeru
My life burns bright.
Ｎｅｖｅｒ　Ｅｎｄｉｎｇ　Ｓｏｕｌ　情熱よ
Never Ending Soul jounetsu yo
Never Ending Soul of passion,
導け　天地を拓け
michibike tenchi wo hirake
guide me and open the path to heaven.
Ｎｅｖｅｒ　Ｅｎｄｉｎｇ　Ｗｏｒｌｄ　打ち立てよう
Never Ending World uchitateyou
Let's create a Never Ending World!
永遠の絆が誇り
eien no kizuna ga hokori
Boasting an eternal bond,
おまえと夢見た世界を　この手に　掴もう
omae to yumemita sekai wo kono te ni tsukamou
you and I will grasp the world we dreamed of.
～♪
Preview
Wang Qi, I will kill you!
（龐煖）王騎 お前を殺す！
（王騎）私のセリフですよ 龐煖！
That's my line, Pang Nuan!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
激突の時！ ほとばしるのは
ただ容赦のない殺意
At the moment they clash
all that gushes out
Confrontation of Supreme Commanders
is merciless intent to kill!
End
Next time,
次回 “総大将 見(まみ)える”